Guide to the Oral History of the American Left Collection OH.002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Tamiment Institute Tapes, circa 1955-1965
  - Industrial Workers of the World Finances and Decline, unidentified IWW REp., undated (Box 83, Audiocassette 14, Box 89)
  - Frank Bohn, Mar 1958; cuid1603 (Box 42)
    Recording regarding the Socialist Party, the Industrial Workers of the World from 1900-1920, and the church and socialism.
  - Call Association, undated; cuid1604; 3 sound tape reels 1/4" (Box 55, Reel cuid1604A, cuid1604B, cuid1604C, E-records tamwag_oh002, E-records cuid1604A, cuid1604B, cuid1604C)
    Format: 1/4" open reel audio, Duration: 45 min.
  - Max Shactman, Dec 31, 1966; cuid1610 (Box 42)
    Recording of a speech titled "The Social Development of Communism."
  - Antonin Souchy, Feb 29, 1960; cuid1612 (Box 42)
  - Sam Weiner, 1962; cuid1617 (Box 42)
    Recording regarding the Industrial Workers of the World from a WCKR Broadcast.
- Aleine Austin Tapes regarding Monthly Review and Highlander Folk School, 1979-1982; cuid1619
  The Tennessee-based Highlander Folk School was founded in 1932 to provide education to activist leaders.
  Monthly Review is a socialist magazine founded in 1949.
  This series contains recordings of interviews by Aleine Austin and an event regarding the history of the Monthly Review.
  Master copies can be found in box 88 and 92
  - Magdoff, Ortiz, Sweezy, undated (Box 88, Audiocassette 1A, 1B, 1A (user), 1B (user))
  - Horton, Myles, August 18-24, 1982 (Box 88, Audiocassette 2A, 2B, 2C, 2D, 2E, 2F, 2A (user), 2B (user), 2C (user), 2D (user), 2E (user), 2F (user))
  - Horton, Magdoff, Ortiz, Sweezy, June 28, 1983 (Box 88, Audiocassette 3, 3 (user))
  - Former Harvard Student, December 10, 1980 (Box 88, Audiocassette 4, 4 (user))
  - Sweezy, Paul, October 23, 1983 (Box 88, Audiocassette 5, 5 (user))
  - Edelman, Harburg, May, December 7, 1980 (Box 88, Audiocassette 6, 6 (user))
  - Monthly Review 30th Anniversary, May 1979 (Box 88, Audiocassette 7A, 7B, 7A (user), 7B (user))
  - Austin, Aleine, undated (Box 88, Audiocassette 8A, 8B, 8C, 8A (user), 8B (user), 8C (user))
- Restricted Interviews in Oral History of the American Left, 1976-1983
  This series contains interviews collected for the Oral History of the American Left that were accepted by the repository as closed, generally for a certain amount of years. The majority of these restrictions are no longer in effect. Upon expiration of restrictions, interviews have been moved to Series I.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Access to interviews in this series is restricted. Interviews for which restrictions have expired have been moved to Series 1. Specific information on the restrictions is available at the interview level. Please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu for more information.
  - Stuart and Elizabeth Ewen, Nov. 7, 1983; cuid1621 (Box Series 7, Box 90, Audiocassette 6A, 6B, Box 91, Audiocassette 1, 2, 2B)
    Interview is closed, except with the permission of the interviewees.
  - Charlotte Stern, 1976; cuid1620 (Box Series 7, Box 90, Audiocassette 7A-7M, Box 91, Audiocassette 1A, 1B, 2, 3A, 3B, 4B, 4D, 5B, 6)
    Interview is closed.
  - Interviews by Alan Wald, 1976-1981; cuid1622 (Box Series 7, Box 90, Audiocassette 1-4, 8A-11B)
    Interviews by Alan Wald on the history of Trotskyism and intellectuals in the United States. Interviewees include Michael Blankfort (Jul 22, 1981), James T. Farrell (May 23, 1976), Leslie Fiedler (May 28, 1981), Nathan Glazer (May 25, 1981), Walter Goldwater (May 10, 1981), and Stan Weir (Sep 26, 1980 and Jul 21, 1981).
- Higley Hill, 2009; cuid1623 (Box 47, Cd Higley Hill)
- Rose Leopold, 2008; cuid1624 (Box 46, Box 47, Cd Rose Leopold)
- Radio Free Maine tapes, 1994-05-13-1994-05-14; cuid36303 (Box 81, Cassette 2-4, Box 9, Folder 11)
  Duration: 200 minutes in three parts
- Remembering Emma, 1990-05-24; cuid36304 (Box Shared Tamiment 176, U-matic 002_001, 002_002)